1887年  羅馬尼亞西部  特蘭西瓦尼亞
它是活的  它活過來了
It's alive. It's alive. It's alive!
他在那兒 用力  再用力
There he is! Hit it again!
成功了
Success!
伯爵  原來是你
Count, it's just you.
你差點就失敗了  維克多
I was beginning to lose faith, Victor.
只可惜你的成功…
A pity your moment of triumph is being spoiled...
卻因為盜墓引起公憤
over a little thing like grave robbery.
是的
Yes.
我必須逃離此地
I must escape this place.
你想逃到哪裡?
Where are you going to run, Victor?
你的實驗品…
Your peculiar experiments have made you unwelcome...
讓你成為眾矢之的
in most of the civilized world.
我要帶他逃得遠遠的
I'll take him away, far away, where no one will ever find him.
不  維克多
No, no, Victor.
我要接管他
The time has come for me to take command of him.
什麼?
What are you saying?
不然我為什麼把城堡借給你
Why do you think I brought you here? Gave you this castle?
-為你建造實驗室? -你說…
-Equipped your laboratory? -You said....
-你相信我的實驗 -沒錯
-You said you believed in my work. -And I do.
但是你自己也說過
But now that it is, as you yourself have said...
這是科學…
a triumph of science...
戰勝上帝的鐵證
over God...
我要用來完成我的目的
it must now serve my purpose.
什麼目的?
What purpose?
老天爺!
Good God!
我寧願死也不會幫你
I would kill myself before helping in such a task.
去死吧!我不需要你了
Feel free. I don't actually need you anymore, Victor.
我只需要他
I just need him.
他才是關鍵
He is the key.
我不能讓他助紂為虐
I could never allow him to be used for such evil.
我可以
I could.
我的新娘非要他不可
In fact, my brides are insisting upon it.
伊果  幫助我
Igor, help me!
你一向對我很好  博士
You have been so kind to me, Doctor...
體諒我  關心我
caring, thoughtful.
但是他付我錢
But he pays me.
退後
Stay back.
你是殺不了我的
You can't kill me, Victor.
我早就死了
I'm already dead.
科學怪人
Dr. Frankenstein!
他要去磨坊  來吧!
Look, it's headed for the windmill! Come on!
苦艾酒
放火燒了它
Burn it! Burn it down!
聖經
吸血鬼
Vampires.
-快跑  快逃命 -吸血鬼!
-Run for your lives! -Vampires!
父親
Father.
一年後-巴黎
懸賞范海辛
兩千法朗
你好
Evening.
你的肉很硬  一定很難消化
You're a big one. You'll be hard to digest.
那真是難為你了
I'd hate to be such a nuisance.
我在倫敦沒逮到你
I missed you in London.
才怪 你射了我一槍
No, you bloody did not! You got me good.
變身怪醫  聖靈騎士下令抓你
Dr. Jekyll, you're wanted by the Knights of the Holy Order...
我現在是海德巨人
It's Mr. Hyde now.
你殺了十二男、六女…
...for the murder of 12 men, six women, four--
四個小孩、三頭山羊 還有一窩子的雞
...children, three goats, and a rather nasty massacre of poultry!
你就是鼎鼎大名的范海辛
So you're the great Van Helsing.
你是喪心病狂的殺人狂
And you're a deranged psychopath.
每個人都有點小毛病
We all have our little problems.
我的上司要我活捉你
My superiors would like for me to take you alive...
把你變回正常人
so that they may extricate your better half.
他們想得美
I bet they bloody would.
我只想宰了你省得麻煩
Personally, I'd rather just kill you and call it a day.
你自己看著辦
But let's make it your decision, shall we?
儘管上吧!
Do let's.
我來也
Here I come...
領死吧!
ready or not!
大笨鐘
The bell!
不  不
No, no.
這一定超痛的
I'll bet that's upsetting.
巴黎夜景超美的
Paris!
給我過來
Come here.
這兒的景觀更贊
I think you'll find the view over here rather spectacular.
很高興認識你  拜了
It's been a pleasure knowing you. Au revoir!
不  不要
Oh, no.
該我了
My turn.
安息吧!
May he rest in peace.
范海辛
Van Helsing.
你這殺人狂
You murderer!
羅馬-梵蒂岡
原諒我  天父  我…
Bless me, Father, for I have--
你犯了罪  我知道
Sinned. Yes, I know. You're very good at that.
你砸爛了聖母院的玫瑰窗
You shattered the Rose Window.
那是海德巨人幹的好事
Not to split hairs, sir, but Mr. Hyde did the shattering.
六百年的古物毀於一旦
13th century. Over 600 years old.
-我真想把你打下地獄 -正好讓我休個假
-I wish you a week in hell for that. -lt would be a nice reprieve.
別誤解我的意思 你斬妖除魔的功力一流
Don't get me wrong. Your results are unquestionable...
只是你樹大招風
but your methods attract far too much attention.
你居然被懸賞通緝 我們很生氣
"Wanted" posters? We are not pleased.
你以為我愛當頭號通緝犯嗎?
Do you think I like being the most wanted man in Europe?
你們為何不幫我想辦法?
Why don't you and the Order do something about it?
因為我們不存在
Because we do not exist.
我也一樣
Well, then neither do l.
當年你半死不活出現在教堂
When we found you crawling up the steps of this church, half-dead...
神派你來替他斬妖除魔
it was clear to all of us that you had been sent to do God's work.
-他幹嘛不自己來? -不准褻瀆上帝
-Why can't he do it himself? -Don't blaspheme.
你就是這樣才會失去記憶
You already lost your memory as a penance for past sins.
你想恢復記憶…
If you wish to recover it...
就要奉命行事
I suggest you continue to heed the call.
沒有我們  黑暗就會籠罩世界
Without us, the world would be in darkness.
統治者和帝王都不可靠
Governments and empires come and go...
只有我們才能捍衛人類世界…
but we have kept mankind safe since time immemorial.
抵抗邪惡力量
We are the last defense against evil.
世人都不知曉的可怕惡魔
An evil that the rest of mankind has no idea even exists.
對你來說它們只是怪物
To you, these monsters are just evil beings to be vanquished.
我卻必須承受…
I'm the one standing there when they die...
殺戮的後果
and become the men they once were.
這是為了試探你的信仰
For you, my good son, this is all a test of faith.
你要遠赴東方
And now, we need you to go to the East.
前往羅馬尼亞邊陲
To the far side of Romania.
一個妖孽橫行的…
An accursed land...
禁忌之地
terrorized by all sorts of nightmarish creatures.
吸血鬼德古拉伯爵的領地
Lorded over by a certain Count Dracula.
- 德古拉? - 對
- Dracula? - Yes.
前所未有的強勁對手
You've never faced one like this before.
450年前…
Our story begins 450 years ago...
一名德蘭斯斐尼亞騎士維拉瑞斯
when a Transylvanian knight named Valerious the Elder...
向上帝保證要消滅吸血鬼…
promised God that his family would never rest nor enter heaven...
否則他的家族將不能上天堂
until they vanquished Dracula from their land.
他們失敗了
They have not succeeded...
家族香火也快斷絕
and they are running out of family.
吉普賽王包瑞斯維拉瑞斯
His descendant Boris Valerious, King of the Gypsies.
他一年前消失無蹤
He disappeared almost 12 months ago.
他的獨子威肯王子 還有他的女兒安娜公主
His only son, Prince Velkan, and his daughter, Princess Anna.
在消滅德古拉前他們若遭到不測
If the two of them are killed before Dracula is vanquished...
那九代的祖先都…
nine generations of their family...
無法進入天堂
will never enter the gates of St. Peter.
這家族四百年來…
For more than four centuries...
為了對抗邪惡
this family has defended our left flank.
付出寶貴的生命
They gave their lives.
我們不能讓他們下地獄
We cannot let them slip into purgatory.
所以你才派我下地獄
So you're sending me into hell.
可以這麼說
In a manner.
維拉瑞斯四百年前留下這卷軸
Valerious the Elder left this here 400 years ago.
不知道用途
We don't know its purpose...
但一定很重要
but he would not have left it lightly.
拉丁文的意思是…
The Latin inscription translates as:
以天父之命打開此門
"ln the name of God, open this door."
上面有徽章
There is an insignia.
沒錯  跟你的戒指一樣
Yes, it matches your ring.
你會在那兒解開你的身世之謎
I think that in Transylvania you may find the answer you seek.
快點、快點
Faster, please. Faster!
就快好了
Getting there.
- 卡爾 - 你來了
- Carl! - There you are.
你有沒有活捉變身怪醫? 還是你殺了他?
Did you bring Mr. Hyde back, or did you kill him?
你殺了他  難怪他們會不爽
You killed him, didn't you? That's why they get so annoyed.
他們可沒叫你帶一具屍體回來
When they ask you to bring someone back, they don't mean as a corpse.
你也心情不好
All right, you're in a mood. Come on.
我有東西保證能讓你開心
I have some things that'll put the bit back in your mouth.
要鑄劍還不簡單
Any idiot can make a sword.
抱歉  神父
Sorry, Father.
- 來吧  卡爾 - 拿去
- Come along, Carl. - Here, take this:
大蒜、聖水…
Rings of garlic, holy water...
銀樁、鎮邪十字架
silver stake, crucifix.
這麼炫的武器我也要
Why can't I have one of those?
你沒殺過吸血鬼  對吧?
You've never gone after vampires before now, have you?
吸血鬼跟其它妖魔鬼怪一樣
Vampires, gargoyles, warlocks, they're all the same.
- 全都該死 - 不  他們不一樣
- Best when cooked well. - No, they're not all the same.
吸血鬼跟惡鬼不同 連我阿嬤都殺得了惡鬼
A vampire is nothing like a warlock. My granny could kill a warlock.
你連大門都不出
Carl, you've never even been out of the abbey.
- 你怎麼知道吸血鬼的事? - 我博學多聞呀!
- How do you know about vampires? - I read.
這是新玩意
Here's something new.
硝酸甘油
Glycerin 48.
抱歉
Sorry!
你有毛病嗎?
What in Allah's name is wrong with you?
他們都嫉妒我
The air around here is thick with envy.
這是我的新發明 瓦斯推動的…
This is my latest invention. It's gas-propelled.
超強除魔火箭弓
Capable of catapulting arrows in rapid succession at tremendous velocity.
只要扣下扳機就行
Just pull the trigger and hold on.
聽說德蘭斯斐尼亞群魔亂舞
I've heard the stories from Transylvania.
你需要這個 這是天才的精心傑作
Trust me, you'll need this. A work of certifiable genius.
- 你真會自賣自誇 - 不是我自誇喲!
- lf you don't say so yourself. - No, I did say so myself.
我是真的多才多藝
I'm a veritable cornucopia of talent.
這也是你發明的?
Did you invent this?
這玩意我研究了十二年
I've been working on that for 12 years.
維蘇威火山的熔漿
It's compressed magma from Mt. Vesuvius...
和來自戈壁沙漠的純鹼
with pure alkaline from the Gobi Desert.
- 獨一無二 - 拿來幹嘛?
- It's one of a kind. - What's it for?
不曉得  不過一定會派上用場
I don't know, but I'm sure it'll come in handy.
你研究了十二年都還沒搞懂?
Twelve years, and you don't know what it does?
我只是不知道它的用途
I didn't say that. I said I didn't know what it's for.
它能製造…
What it does is to create a light source...
跟太陽一樣強的光亮
equal to the intensity of the sun.
用來做什麼?
This will come in handy how?
不曉得 把敵人的眼睛閃瞎
I don't know. You can blind your enemies.
或是烤BBQ
Charbroil a herd of charging wildebeest.
你自己動動腦筋嘛!
Use your imagination.
我不用動腦筋  你要跟我來
No, I'm gonna use yours. That's why you're coming with me.
- 我才不幹咧! - 你罵了髒話
- Holy hell be damned I am! - You cursed.
罵得很爛
Not very well,
你是和尚  不該罵髒話
but you're a monk. You shouldn't curse at all.
我只是修道士  愛罵就罵
Actually, I'm still just a friar. I can curse all I want...
該死!
damn it!
主教命令你幫助我
The Cardinal has ordered you to keep me alive.
- 活得越久越好 - 我不搞這一套啦!
- For as long as possible. - But I'm not a field man.
范海辛
Van Helsing
我真的不想去德蘭斯斐尼亞
I don't want to go to Transylvania.
來吧!
Come on.
德古拉派你來一定有原因
Dracula unleashed you for a reason.
快把我拉上去
Pull me up!
卡住了!
It's stuck!
- 不  安娜  它會吃了你 - 我哥哥有危險
- No, Anna, it will kill you! - That's my brother out there.
把繩子切斷
Cut the rope! Cut it now!
威肯!
Velkan!
快去拿我的槍
My gun! Find my gun!
快去  一定要用銀彈
Find Velkan's gun. It has to be the silver bullets.
安娜!快點!
Anna, hurry!
讓開!
Move.
安娜!小心!
Anna, look out!
快跑!
Run!
威肯
Velkan.
神啊!
God...
請幫助我們
help us.
- 你到底還記得些什麼? - 卡爾  我現在不想談
- So, what do you remember? - Not now, Carl.
你一定記得些什麼
There must be something.
我記得在馬薩達對抗過羅馬大軍
I remember fighting the Romans at Masada.
- 那是千年前的事! - 是你要問的
- That was in 73 A.D. - You asked.
我們來這裡做什麼?
What are we doing here?
幹嘛非得殺死吸血鬼德古拉?
Why is it so important to kill this Dracula, anyway?
- 因為他是惡魔之子 - 除此之外呢?
- Because he's the son of the Devil. - I mean, besides that.
殺了他  他的徒子徒孫也會死
If we kill him, anything bitten or created by him will also die.
還有咧?
I mean, besides that.
歡迎來到德蘭斯斐尼亞
Welcome to Transylvania.
- 你總是這麼顧人怨嗎? - 差不多
- ls it always like this? - Pretty much.
你們  轉過來
You, turn around.
- 給我看看 - 為什麼?
- Let me see your faces. - Why?
我們不信任陌生人
Because we don't trust strangers.
陌生人不受歡迎
Strangers don't last long here.
長170公分  寬70公分
5'7" by 2'3".
兩位  交出武器
Gentlemen, you will now be disarmed.
試試看
You can try.
你敢不聽我的話?
You refuse to obey our laws?
- 我誰都不甩 - 好吧!
- The laws of men mean little to me. - Fine.
殺了他們
Kill them.
- 我是來幫你的 - 我不需要幫忙
- I'm here to help you. - I don't need any help.
真的嗎?
Really?
快進去!
Everybody inside!
快把小孩子藏起來!
Hide the children!
留下來
Stay here.
你才留下來  她們想殺我
You stay here. They're trying to kill me.
- 蜜西卡  殺了陌生人 - 我很樂意
- Marishka, kill the stranger. - Love to.
快跑!
Run!
卡爾  十字弓沒有用
Carl, it's not working.
瞄準她們的心臟
Try aiming at their hearts.
她們怕太陽
It's the sun.
范海辛?
Van Helsing.
你想飛嗎?
Do you like to fly, Anna?
哈羅  安娜
Hello, Anna.
你好嗎? 艾莉拉
Nice to see you, too, Aleera.
我上輩子欠你一命嗎?
Did I do something to you in a past life?
少裝蒜
Don't play coy with me, Princess.
其實你想什麼我很清楚
I know what lurks in your lusting heart.
你自己要小心點
I hope you have a heart, Aleera...
有一天我會殺了你
because someday I'm going to drive a stake through it.
這玩意很有用
This should do the trick.
聖水
Holy water!
別浪費時間  幹掉他
Stop your teasing, Marishka, and finish him.
殺了他有點可惜
Too bad. So sad.
教堂聖水
The church!
三十歲
Thirty years old.
年紀正好
Perfectly aged.
親愛的安娜
Hello, Anna, my dear.
維拉瑞斯家族最後成員
The last of the Valerious.
我要狂吸她的鮮血
I can feel fresh blood rushing through her veins.
她來了
Here she comes!
我要吸第一口
I want first bite.
- 他殺死吸血鬼新娘 - 他殺死蜜西卡
- He killed a bride! - He killed Marishka!
你殺了蜜西卡!
You killed Marishka!
- 你殺了吸血鬼! - 這樣不好嗎?
- You killed a vampire! - But isn't that a good thing?
吸血鬼不得已才吸人血
Vampires only kill what they need to survive.
一個月最多殺一、兩人
One or two people a month.
現在他們會大開殺戒
Now they will kill for revenge.
- 你粉受歡迎耶 - 我是萬人迷
- Are you always this popular? - Pretty much.
你的墓碑上要刻什麼名字?
So what name, my good sir, do I carve on your gravestone?
他叫范海辛
His name is Van Helsing.
你真是臭名遠播
Your reputation precedes you.
下次跟緊點  你死了就沒用
Next time stay close. You're no good to me dead.
你挺帶種的嘛!
Well, I'll say this for you. You've got courage.
他是百年來擒殺吸血鬼第一人
He's the first one to kill a vampire in over 100 years.
絕對有資格喝一杯
I'd say that's earned him a drink.
蜜西卡
Marishka!
他們怎麼不饒過我們?
Why can't they just leave us alone?
我們從不濫殺無辜
We never kill more than our fill and less than our share.
他們辦得到嗎?
Can they say the same?
我叫你們…
Did I not stress how important it was...
幹掉魏氏家族
to be finished with Anna Valerious...
我們就快實現夢想了
before she destroys what we are trying to create?
- 蜜西卡死了 - 主人
- We lost Marishka. - Master.
親愛的  別擔心
There, there, my darlings. Do not worry.
- 我會找另一個新娘 - 什麼?
- I shall find another bride. - What?
- 你嫌棄我們嗎? - 你好沒良心哦!
- Do we mean so little to you? - Have you no heart?
我沒有良心  也沒有愛
No, I have no heart! I feel no love!
沒有恐懼
Nor fear...
沒有喜悅
nor joy...
更沒有悲傷
nor sorrow!
我也沒有感覺
I am hollow.
但是我有不死之身
And I will live forever.
- 主人 - 其實沒這麼糟
- My Lord. - lt is not so bad.
我與全世界為敵
I am at war with the world...
還有世上的每種生物
and every living soul in it.
大戰即將展開
But soon the final battle will begin.
我要摸清敵人的底細
I must go and find out who our new visitor is.
咱們要吸他的血當餐前酒
You will have to make a little aperitif out of him.
我不能讓他壞了我們的大事
We are much too close to success to be interrupted now.
- 不 - 上次的實驗失敗
- No! - The last experiment was a failure!
求求你別再嘗試
Please, say you will not try again.
我無法承受再失敗的痛苦
My heart could not bear the sorrow if we fail again.
過來
Come.
別害怕
Do not fear me.
世人都畏懼我
Everybody else fears me.
我的新娘不必怕我
Not my brides.
伊果
lgor.
是  主人
Yes, master.
你為何虐待這可憐蟲?
Why do you torment that thing so?
人性本惡呀!
It's what I do.
你要記住  己所不欲…
Remember, lgor, "Do unto others...."
必施於人
Before they do unto me, master.
回去吧!
Now go, all of you!
全都給我去法蘭肯斯坦堡
To Castle Frankenstein!
對  我們再試一次
Yes, we will try again.
- 你們是怎麼來的? - 走海路
- So, how did you get here? - We came by sea.
- 真的?海路? - 是的
- Really? The sea? - Well, yes.
- 亞得里亞海? - 吸血鬼住在哪裡?
- The Adriatic Sea? - Where do I find Dracula?
四世紀前他住在這兒
He used to live in this very house four centuries ago.
現在沒人知道他的巢穴
No one knows where he lives now.
我父親總是盯著那幅畫…
Father would stare at that painting for hours...
找答案
Iooking for Dracula's lair.
- 你為什麼要來? - 我能幫助你
- So that's why you've come? - I can help you.
- 誰也幫不了我 - 我可以試試
- No one can help me. - I can try.
我全家都死光光了
You can die trying. All of my family has.
- 我能保護自己 - 才怪
- I can handle this myself. - So I noticed.
這次吸血鬼在白天出擊
The vampires attacked in daylight. They never do that.
我沒有準備  下次不會了
I was unprepared. It won't happen again.
他們為什麼白天出擊?
So why did they attack in daylight?
好讓我措手不及
Clearly they wanted to catch me off guard.
他們想除掉我全家
They seem almost desperate to finish off my family.
- 為什麼要在現在? - 你很愛問耶
- Why is that? Why now? - You ask a lot of questions.
我通常只會問…
Usually I ask only two:
對手是誰? 怎麼殺他?
What are we dealing with? How do I kill it?
父親終其一生在尋找答案
My father spent most of his life looking for answers year after year.
他翻遍了高塔的文獻
Tearing through the tower, combing through the family archives.
- 卡爾  從高塔找起 - 好的
- Carl, the tower. Start there. - Right.
你不能比吸血鬼先死
The only way to save your family is to stay alive till Dracula's killed.
除了我誰能殺他? 除了我誰有這勇氣?
And who will kill him if not me? Who will show courage if not me?
你一個人勢單力薄
Go alone and you'll be outmanned and outpositioned.
晚上也看不到他
And you can't see in the dark.
我們明天一早再獵殺他
In the morning, we will hunt him...
一起行動
but we'll do it together.
有人說你是殺人狂
Some say you're a murderer, Mr. Van Helsing.
有人說你是聖人 你到底是什麼?
Others say you're a holy man. Which is it?
都是吧!
It's a bit of both, I think.
- 我答應請你喝一杯 - 沒錯
- I promised you a drink. - Yes, you did.
酒吧在那兒  請自便
The bar is down the hall. Help yourself.
失陪了  我要去殺吸血鬼
As for me, I'm going to finish this once and for all.
你不該單獨背負這重擔
Sorry you've to carry this burden alone.
這是我一個人的責任
On the contrary, I would wish for it no other way.
我為你父兄的死感到遺憾
I'm sorry about your father and brother.
我會再見到他們
I will see them again.
我們對死很看得開
We Transylvanians always look on the brighter side of death.
- 你不怕死 - 對  你只是看不透
- There's a brighter side of death? - Yes. It's just harder to see.
很對不起
I'm sorry about that, too.
該死的范海辛
Van Helsing!
范海辛?
Van Helsing?
- 威肯? - 安娜
- Velkan? - Anna.
老天  你還活著
Oh, my God, you're alive.
我的時間不多
No. Anna, I only have a moment.
- 剛才有一隻狼… - 別管了
- But there's a werewolf-- - Listen to me!
我知道德古拉的秘密…
I know Dracula's secret. He has a....
- 威肯? - 求求你
- Velkan? - Please.
不!
No!
快跑
Run, Anna.
安娜
Anna!
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
怎麼會有狗臭味?
Why does it smell like wet dog in here?
狼人!
Werewolf!
沒錯  你需要銀彈
Right. You'll be needing silver bullets, then.
好樣的
Well done.
誰在獵捕誰呀?
Who's hunting whom?
夜色真美 我睡這具棺材太窄了
Nice night. This is a bit tight for me.
你睡正好
But for you it's a perfect fit.
真巧
What a coincidence.
你沒被狼人吃掉
I see the wolf man hasn't killed you yet.
他很想
Don't worry, he's getting to it.
- 你好像不怕他 - 我對他不造成威脅
- You don't seem bothered. - I'm no threat to him.
我負責替他收拾殘局
I'm just the one who cleans up after him...
你了嗎?
if you get my meaning.
這麼晚還在挖墳?
Little late to be digging graves, isn't it?
墳墓永遠挖不完
Never too late to dig graves.
誰曉得幾時又會死人
You never know when you'll need a fresh one.
抱歉 本性難移
Oh, sorry. It's just my nature.
- 讓開 - 不
- Move! - No!
- 為什麼? - 你會掐死我!
- Why? - You're choking me!
- 快說! - 我不能讓別人知道…
- Give me a reason not to. - I can't. If people knew....
他不是你哥哥了
He's not your brother anymore, Anna!
- 你已經知道了?  - 是的
- You knew?  -Yes.
在我阻止你之前或之後?
Before or after I stopped you from shooting him?
之前
Before.
你還是向他下手
And still you tried to kill him!
他是狼人! 他會吃人!
He's a werewolf! He's gonna kill people!
他也不願意! 那不是他的錯!
He can't help it! It's not his fault!
但是他還是會吃人!
I know, but he'll do it anyway!
你不懂得寬恕嗎?
Do you understand forgiveness?
我會請上帝寬恕他們
Yes. I ask for it often.
聽說德古拉有解藥
They say Dracula has a cure.
只要有任何的可能性…
If there's a chance I can save my brother...
- 我要找來救我哥 - 不
- I'm going after it. - No.
- 我要找到德古拉 - 我要找到我哥
- I need to find Dracula. - And I need to find my brother!
他是我唯一的家人
He gave his life for me. He's the only family I have left.
我比誰都更痛恨德古拉
I despise Dracula more than you can ever imagine.
他害我孤零零一個人在世上
He has taken everything from me, leaving me alone in this world.
擁有痛失親人的記憶…
To have memories of those you loved and lost...
比失去記憶更難過
is perhaps harder than to have no memories at all.
好吧!
All right.
我們去找你哥哥
We'll look for your brother.
- 伊果 - 是  主人
- lgor. - Yes, master.
- 好了沒? - 就快好了
- How long before we are ready? - Soon, master. Very soon.
可惜你把博士殺死了
It is difficult without the good doctor...
不過矮靈族很有用
but the Dwergi, they are doing well?
不
No!
那就好
Good.
這是我的個人恩怨 我要替我全家報仇雪恨
For me, this is all personal. It's all about family and honor.
你為什麼要斬妖除魔? 你能得到什麼?
Why do you do it, this job of yours? What do you hope to get out of it?
也許是為了尋找自我
I don't know. Maybe some self-realization.
你到現在得到什麼?
What have you got out of it so far?
無止盡的惡夢
Nightmares.
狼人尚未被詛咒完全控制之前…
Werewolves only shed before the first full moon.
會在第一次月圓之前開始脫皮
Before the curse has completely consumed them.
- 這是哪裡? - 法蘭肯斯坦堡
- What is this place? - Castle Frankenstein.
應該沒人在
But it should be abandoned.
我不懂
I don't understand.
這兒的主人一年前遇害
The man who lived here was killed a year ago.
- 他是盜墓者 - 一年前
- A grave robber, among other things. - A year ago.
你父親一年前失蹤
It was just after that your father went missing.
他為了抓吸血鬼 準備去海邊
Yes. He was looking for Dracula. He was on his way to the sea.
我沒見過大海
I have never been to the sea.
一定很美
I'll bet it's beautiful.
狼人一碰到月圓就抓狂
Werewolves are such a nuisance during their first full moon.
難以控制
So hard to control.
我派你…
I send you on a simple errand...
去摸清敵人的底細
to find out who our new visitor is...
你卻去找老妹聊天
and you have to stop for a little chat with your sister.
別傷害她 她不知道你的秘密
Leave her out of this, Count. She doesn't know your secret.
我死也不會說
And I am soon to take it to my grave.
你不能死  你對我還有用
Don't wish for death so quickly. I intend for you to be quite useful.
我死也不會幫你
I would rather die than help you.
別傻了  說這種話一定會掛
Don't be boring. Everyone who says that dies.
今晚…
Besides, tonight...
一過午夜…
after the final stroke of midnight...
你就必須唯我是從
you will have no choice but to obey me.
很眼熟吧?
Look familiar?
父親?
Father?
不!
No!
他沒什麼用
He proved useless.
我希望你變成狼人…
But I'm hoping, with werewolf venom running through your veins...
比較好用
you will be of greater benefit!
我殺不了你  我妹妹一定會
I may have failed to kill you, Count, but my sister will not.
不  不要
Never!
- 矮靈族 - 矮靈族?
- Dwergi. - Dwergi?
德古拉的爪牙 刻苦耐勞、兇狠殘暴
Dracula's servants. Industrious but extremely vicious.
你得先下手為強
If you get the chance to kill one, do it...
- 不然就會死得很慘 - 知道了
- because they'll do worse to you. - Right.
他們利用威肯做實驗
They say they're using my brother in some sort of experiment.
我哥還在自我掙扎
My brother is still battling the sickness within him.
- 他還有一線希望 - 安娜
- There's still hope. - Anna.
他沒有救了
There is no hope for your brother.
我們得殺了德古拉
But we can still protect others by killing Dracula.
開始吧!
Let us begin!
抬起來
No slacking! Up!
- 你見過這東西沒?  - 沒
- You ever see these things before? - No
- 是什麼? - 吸血鬼寶寶
- What do you think they are? - Offspring.
什麼?
What?
他跟三個美女混了四百年耶
A man with three gorgeous women for 400 years.
吸血鬼是活死人
Yes, vampires are the walking dead.
後代一出生就死了
It only makes sense their children are born dead.
他想讓他們復活
He's obviously trying to bring them to life.
女士優先
Ladies first.
他們每個月都殺一、兩人
Dracula and his brides only kill one or two people a month.
這些小吸血鬼活過來就慘了
If he brings all these things to life....
- 打開開關 - 是  主人
- Throw the switches! - Yes, master.
你在幹嘛?
What are you doing?
摸清敵人底細
I want to see what we're up against.
原來這就是吸血鬼寶寶
So this is what you get when vampires mate.
來吧!
Come on!
他們該吸血了 去教他們  快去
They need to feed. Teach them how. Teach them!
向魔鬼祈禱…
And beg the Devil...
這次他們能活下去
that this time they stay alive.
- 該我上場了 - 等等
- This is where I come in. - No, wait!
來領死吧!
Now that I have your attention....
有意思
Yes, well, that's interesting.
慘了  我得警告大家
That's not good. Must warn somebody.
心跳能透露一個人的個性
I can tell the character of a man by the sound of his heartbeat.
平常人只要看到我…
Usually when I approach...
心跳就會加速
I can almost dance to the beat.
你的心跳卻很穩定
Strange that yours is so steady.
快一點!
Hurry up!
一定要讓空氣充滿電力
We must keep the atmosphere electrified!
加強發電機
Accelerate the generators!
發出電擊
Power the dynamos!
失去動力了
We are losing power.
這傢伙沒有用
The human is insufficient.
威肯
Velkan.
我的天
Oh, my God.
去吸血吧!乖孩子
Feed, my darlings! Feed!
安息吧!
May he rest in peace.
你好  蓋布歐
Hello, Gabriel.
我們不能讓主人絕子絕孫
We must not lose the master's progeny!
這玩意傷不了我
Is this your silver stake?
咱們有多久沒見了? 三、四百年?
How long has it been? 300, 400 years?
你不記得了  對吧?
You don't remember, do you?
記得什麼?
Exactly what is it I should be remembering?
你是偉大的范海辛
You are the great Van Helsing.
西藏喇嘛親手調教的怪物獵人
Trained by monks and mullahs from Tibet to lstanbul.
受到羅馬教廷的保護
Protected by Rome herself.
但卻跟我一樣被世人唾棄
But, like me, hunted by all others.
聖靈騎士對你瞭若指掌
The Knights of the Holy Order know all about you.
你當然查過我的底細
It's no surprise you would know about me.
事情沒那麼簡單
Yes, but it's much more than this.
我跟你的交情非淺
We have such history, you and l, Gabriel.
你為什麼會做可怕的噩夢?
Have you ever wondered why you have such horrible nightmares?
夢到古老戰場的慘烈殺戮
Horrific scenes of ancient battles past.
你怎麼會知道?
How do you know me?
- 威肯 - 安娜
- Velkan. - Anna.
別救我  住手
No. Don't unstrap me.
別這麼做  住手
No, you must not! No! Stop!
住手 我要救你出去
Stop it. I'm getting you out of here.
威肯  沒關係 我帶你回家
Velkan, it's all right. I'm taking you home.
你要我喚起你的記憶?
So would you like me to refresh your memory a little?
說出你幹過的壞事?
A few details from your sordid past.
改天再聊吧!
Perhaps that is a conversation for another time.
讓我重新自我介紹
Allow me to reintroduce myself.
我是范斯勞德古拉伯爵
I am Count Vladislaus Dragulia.
1422年出生
Born 1422.
1462年遇害
Murdered 1462.
救命啊!救救我
Help me!
咱們待太久了
I think we've overstayed our welcome.
- 找到小孩了嗎? - 還沒
- Have you found the children? - Not yet.
- 怎麼回事? - 他們掛掉了
- What happened? - They just died.
我該怎麼報答你?
How can I ever repay you?
不行啦!你是和尚耶
But you can't do that. You are a monk.
其實我只是修道士
Well, actually I'm just a friar.
對不起  我們盡了全力
I am sorry, master. We try and we try...
但只有法蘭肯斯坦博士才有辦法
but I fear we are not so smart as Dr. Frankenstein.
沒錯
Truly.
看來他把復活之鑰帶進棺材
It would appear the good doctor took the key to life to his grave.
找到他們
Hunt them down.
把他們殺了
Kill them both.
銀樁? 十字架?
A silver stake? A crucifix?
你以為我們沒試過嗎?
What, did you think we haven't tried everything before?
我們無所不用其極
We've shot him, stabbed him, clubbed him...
但是連聖水…
sprayed him with holy water, staked him through the heart...
都殺不了他
and still he lives! Do you understand?
沒人知道該怎麼殺他
No one knows how to kill Dracula.
你早說嘛!
Well, I could have used that information a little earlier.
別這樣看我
Don't give me that look.
你說的對  對不起
You were right. I'm sorry.
他不是我哥哥了
He's not my brother anymore.
你有家人嗎?
Do you have any family, Mr. Van Helsing?
不曉得  我也想知道
Not sure. I hope to find out someday.
這就是我的動力
That's what keeps me going.
- 這才是你的動力 - 苦艾酒  很烈哦!
- Here's to what keeps you going. - Absinthe. Strong stuff.
別碰到舌頭  否則的話…
Don't let it touch your tongue. It'll knock you on your--
吸血鬼
Vampire.
吸血鬼!
Vampires!
我記起來了
Now I remember.
就算擁有一顆純潔虔誠的心
"Even a man who is pure in heart And says his prayers by night
每逢月圓之夜
"May become a wolf when the wolfbane blooms
也可能變成一個狼人
"And the moon is shining bright
或是在日落後吸食人血
"Or crave another's blood when the sun goes down
振翅而飛
"And his body takes to flight"
下麵有怪物
There's something down here.
他會吃人
And it's carnivorous.
他看起來是人類
Whatever it is, it appears to be human.
他穿17號鞋 重164公斤
I'd say he's a size 17. Around 360 pounds.
高270公分
8.5 to 9 feet tall.
右腳有點跛 有三顆銅牙
He has a bad gimp in his right leg and three copper teeth.
你怎麼知道?
How do you know he has copper teeth?
他就在你後面  快閃
Because he's standing right behind you. Move!
天啊!科學怪人
Oh, my God! The Frankenstein monster!
我才不是怪物
Monster? Who's the monster here?
我又沒做壞事
I have done nothing wrong...
你們卻想置我於死地
and yet you and your kind all wish me dead!
你想要什麼?
What do you want?
我想活
To exist.
住手!
Don't!
- 一定要斃了他 - 等等
- We must kill it. - Wait.
如果你們不想害死人類
If you value your lives and the lives of your kind...
- 最好把我給殺了 - 不
- you will kill me. - No.
德古拉一直想找我
If Dracula finds me....
我是起死回生的關鍵
I am the key to my father's machine.
我是生命之鑰
The key to life.
我能讓吸血鬼後裔活過來
Life for Dracula's children.
他昨晚讓他們活過來
He already awakened them last night.
兩個
Two.
那只是一個吸血鬼新娘…
And those were from only one bride.
一胎生出來的孩子
From one single birthing.
上次他們也不能存活
And they died as they did the last time he tried.
只有我能讓他們獲得永生
Only with me can he give them lasting life.
還有更多嗎?
There are more? More of those things?
成千…
Thousands.
上萬
Thousands more.
- 不要 - 你也聽到他的話
- No. - You heard what he said.
消滅邪惡是我的使命和責任
My life, my job is to vanquish evil.
我的直覺很靈
I can sense evil.
邪惡力量造出…
This thing, man, whatever it is...
這個科學怪人
evil may have created it, may have left its mark on it.
他本身卻不邪惡  我不能殺他
But evil does not rule it, so I cannot kill it.
- 我可以 - 休想
- I can. - Not while I'm here.
你家人一直想消滅德古拉
Your family has spent 400 years trying to kill Dracula.
也許他能幫忙
Maybe this poor creature can help us find a way.
糟了  我們被發現了
Oh, my God. He's seen us.
他們一定會找到他
Now they'll come for him.
只憑我們兩個人阻止不了他們
Neither you nor l will be able to stop them.
我只要帶他到羅馬就安全
If I can get him to Rome, we can protect him there.
那幅畫活過來…
And then the painting came alive...
怪獸自相殘殺
and the two creatures attacked each other.
- 這代表什麼? - 不知道
- What does it mean? - I don't know.
卡爾  別盯著他看
Listen, Carl, whatever you do, don't stare at him.
我在盯著他看
I'm staring at him.
他是一個人嗎?
Is that a man?
他是七個人拼湊出來的
Actually, seven men. Parts, anyway.
我被他們抓到…
By exposing me, you have condemned me!
人類就會滅亡
Me and all of humanity!
德蘭斯斐尼亞駿馬…
Nothing is faster than Transylvanian horses.
比狼人更快
Not even a werewolf.
碰到別的怪物就沒轍
Anything else, you're on your own.
- 讓我走 - 你要走去哪兒?
- Let me go. - Where are you going to go?
照照鏡子吧!
I don't know if you've seen a mirror lately...
你很顯眼耶
but you kind of stick out in a crowd.
德蘭斯斐尼亞
喀爾巴阡山脈
布達佩斯
不能讓科學怪人喪命
We must not let the creature be destroyed!
快去救科學怪人
Save him! Save the monster!
銀樁!
Stakes!
不!
No!
卡爾
Carl
我的老天
Oh, my God.
你在幹嘛?
What are you doing out here?
別放手!
Don't let go!
我能幫忙!
I can help!
你不會殺我?
You won't kill me?
你得趕快放開我
Only if you don't hurry!
快跳
Jump!
安娜
Anna...
原諒我
forgive me.
我們會再相見
I will see you again.
你殺了他
You killed him.
所以我才是殺人狂
Now you know why they call me murderer.
天啊!
Oh, my God.
你被咬了
You've been bitten.
你害主人傷透腦筋
So much trouble to my master. So much trouble.
你要什麼?
What do you want?
主人要跟你交換
The master commands a trade.
用安娜公主交換科學怪人
The monster for the Princess.
在大庭廣眾的地方
Somewhere public. Lots of people.
你主人不會…
A place where your master will be less inclined...
露出猙獰面目
to expose his other side.
明晚是萬聖夜
Tomorrow night is All Hallows' Eve.
布達佩斯有一場盛大化妝舞會
Here in Budapest there is a wonderful masquerade ball.
- 你沒事吧? - 沒事
- Are you all right? - No.
他被狼人…
He has been bitten.
咬了
Bitten by a werewolf.
你會變成你獵殺的怪物
Now you will become that which you have hunted so passionately.
很抱歉
I am sorry.
希望別人也一樣會獵殺你
May others be as passionate in their hunting of you.
他在這兒很安全
Well, they won't find him in here.
這真是罪過
I'm sure this is some sort of sin.
別擔心  上帝會饒恕我們的 我們必須救出安娜
God will forgive us. We need to save Anna.
這頂帽子會不會太炫?
You don't think the hat's a bit much?
- 幫幫忙 - 好
- Carl, help me! - Right.
咱們破了幾誡呀?
How many commandments can we break in one day?
根據書上記載…
Anyway, according to the book...
你在第一個月圓才會變成狼人
you won't turn into a werewolf until the rising of your first full moon.
也就是兩天后
That's two nights from now.
這兩天你還有抵抗能力
You'll still be able to fight Dracula's hold over you...
直到兩天后的半夜
until the final stroke of midnight.
- 我一點都不擔心 - 你應該害怕才對
- So I have nothing to worry about. - My God, you should be terrified.
- 多謝了 - 抱歉
- Thanks. - Sorry.
一定要在兩天內想出辦法
We still have 48 hours to find a solution.
你確定他出不去?
You sure he can't get out of there?
除非有死人頭幫忙
Not without some help from the dead.
當我的傀儡感覺如何?
How does it feel to be a puppet on my string?
我不會讓你交換我
I won't let you trade me, Count.
我不會交換你
I have no intention of trading you.
我很瞭解范海辛
And if I know Van Helsing, which I do...
他也不會交換
he is not planning on making a trade, either.
我們都沒這麼容易打發
Neither of us has ever settled for half.
他們在那兒
There they are.
你讓我不寒而粟
You make my skin crawl.
我會讓你熱情如火
This is not all I could do with your skin.
幫我一個忙
Carl, I need you to do something.
我不會喜歡  對吧?
I'm not gonna like this, am l?
咱們真是速配
Don't we make a lovely couple?
我的天
Oh, my God.
我在找一個新娘
I am looking for a new bride, Anna.
美麗堅強
Someone strong and beautiful.
你只要忍一忍痛
One brief moment of pain...
我們就能永遠在一起
and we can be together forever.
你沒有心跳
You have no heartbeat.
也許你可以…
Perhaps it just needs...
讓我心動
to be rekindled.
安娜  醒醒
Anna. Anna! Wake up.
蓋布歐
Gabriel.
歡迎來到我的夏宮
Welcome to my summer palace.
主人  你看
Master! Look, master!
我們抓到他了
We have him, master.
怎樣會  活死人…
You wretched undead...
我會報仇的
I shall have my revenge!
我雖走過死亡蔭穀
"Though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death...
但是卻不怕邪惡
"l shall fear no evil."
你們只是受詛咒的…
You are nothing but damned bones...
靈魂
and damned souls...
將受到地獄烈焰焚燒
and will burn in the flames of Hell!
事情終於搞定了
Now that everything is as it should be...
各位先生女士  容我介紹…
Ladies and gentlemen, I give to you...
范海辛
Van Helsing!
走吧!
Come on.
快呀!
好
Yes!
我知道怎麼用這玩意了
Now I know what it's for.
- 怎麼走? - 那扇窗
- Where are we going? - Through that window!
你真是個天才
Carl, you're a genius!
我只是有一些勁爆道具
A genius with access to unstable chemicals.
跟他們說拜拜吧
Say goodbye to your friends.
我會找到你的 我對天發誓
I'll find you! I'll get you back and set you free!
我會去救你
I swear to God!
- 我一定要救他 - 不行
- I must save him. - No, you can't.
為什麼?
Why?
我請示過羅馬教廷
I cabled Rome earlier to apprise them of our situation.
- 怎麼樣? - 就算你殺了吸血鬼
- What did they say? - Even if you kill Dracula...
一樣要毀了科學怪人
Rome orders you to destroy Frankenstein as well.
他並不邪惡
He isn't evil.
他們說他不是人
But they say he isn't human, either.
他們憑什麼這麼說?
Do they know him? Have they spoken to him? Who are they to judge?
他會被用來毀滅人類
They want you to destroy him so he can never be used to harm humanity.
那我呢?我也該死嗎?
What of me? Did you tell them what I'm to become?
他們有沒有教你怎麼殺我?
Did they tell you how to kill me?
如何正確的使用銀樁?
The correct angle of the stake as it enters my heart?
你該用多少銀彈?
The exact measure of silver in each bullet?
- 住手! - 我沒提起你
- Stop! - No, I left you out!
對不起
I'm sorry.
我快變身了
It's starting.
他們把儀器帶到吸血鬼巢穴
They must have taken all the equipment to Dracula's lair.
不知道在哪兒
Wherever that is.
還有時間
Look, there's still time.
他要到晚上才能行動
Dracula can't bring his children to life until the sun sets.
只有兩小時
The sun sets in two hours.
我們花了四百年都找不到他
We've been looking for him for more than 400 years!
這次有我在  安啦!
Yes, well, I wasn't around for those 400 years, now, was l?
你發現什麼?
Okay, Carl, what have you learned?
德古拉是維拉瑞斯之子
That Count Dracula was actually the son of Valerious the Elder.
也就是你的祖先
The son of your ancestor.
大家都知道  還有呢?
Everybody knows that. What else?
根據文獻記載…
All right. Well, according to this rubbing...
他遭到謀殺
it all started when Dracula was murdered.
- 兇手是誰? - 不知道
- Do you know who murdered him? - No,
上面只提到上帝的左手
there's just some vague reference to the Left Hand of God.
1462年他死時…
And in 1462, when Dracula died...
- 和魔鬼交易 - 並被賜予新生
- he made a covenant with the Devil. - And was given a new life.
但是他必須吸食人血
But the only way he could sustain that life was by drinking blood.
讓我說完  好唄
Excuse me. Are you going to let me tell the story?
抱歉
Sorry.
你的祖先因為這個不肖子…
And your ancestor, having sired this evil creature...
前往羅馬請求教廷寬恕
went to Rome to seek forgiveness. That's when the bargain was made.
他要殺死德古拉…
He was to kill Dracula...
才能延續家族香火
in return for eternal salvation of his entire family...
一直到你為止
right down the line all the way to you.
但是他無法對…
But he couldn't do it.
親生兒子下毒手
As evil as Dracula was, my ancestor couldn't kill his own son.
他把德古拉放逐到冰封城堡
So he banished him to an icy fortress...
送入一道一去不返的門
sending him through a door from which there was no return.
- 但是魔鬼給他翅膀 - 沒錯
- And then the Devil gave him wings. - Yes.
- 這道門在哪裡? - 不知道
- All right, so where is this door? - I don't know.
你的祖先留下線索
But when your ancestor couldn't kill his son, he left clues.
好讓後代子孫完成任務
So that future generations might do it for him.
我父親就是在這裡…
That must be what my father was looking for in here.
尋找這道門的線索
Clues to the door's location.
門
The door.
我知道了
Of course.
你父親成天…
You said your father spent hours...
都盯著這幅畫
staring at this painting, trying to find the lair.
我想你是對的
I think you were right. Quite literally.
這就是那道門 只是他打不開
I think this is the door. He just didn't know how to open it.
拉丁文
Look. A Latin inscription.
搞不好我會讀
Maybe it works like the painting in the tower.
是的話我父親早就打開了
If this were a door, my father would have opened it long ago.
少了一塊  讀不出來
I can't finish the inscription. There's a piece missing.
德蘭斯斐尼亞
- 你父親沒有這個 - 你從哪兒來的?
- Your father didn't have this. - Where did you get that?
拼起來
Carl, finish it.
以上帝之名打開此門
In the name of God, open this door.
一面鏡子
A mirror.
德古拉沒有倒影
Dracula has no reflection in the mirror.
為什麼?
But why?
也許這對他來說並不是鏡子
Maybe, to Dracula it's not a mirror at all.
好冷  在下雪
It's cold. And it's snowing.
到另一邊見
See you on the other side.
小心點
Be careful.
德古拉堡
Castle Dracula.
最好想出一個計謀
Do we have a plan?
三個臭皮匠…
Doesn't have to be Wellington's at Waterloo...
勝過一個諸葛亮
but some sort of plan would be nice.
我們進去阻止德古拉
We're going to stop Dracula.
誰敢擋路就格殺勿論
And kill anything in our way.
祝你們好運喔!
Well, you let me know how that goes.
雖然這兒很暖和…
Well, as grateful as I am to be out of the cold...
不過這可不是好事
that doesn't seem like a good thing.
快走吧!
We'd better get moving.
- 這些全是… - 沒錯
- So are all of those-- - Yes.
- 裡面都是… - 對
- And inside them are-- - Yes.
從早到晚就知道使喚人
Igor do this! Igor do that!
怎麼會?不可能
How did you find.... It's impossible!
- 求求你別殺我 - 為什麼?
- Please don't kill me! - Why not?
因為…
Well, l....
主人醒來了
My master has awakened.
- 有解藥 - 什麼?
- There is a cure. - What?
德古拉有狼人的解藥
Dracula. He has a cure to remove the curse of the werewolf!
快去找解藥救你自己
Go, find the cure! Save yourself!
快去找吧!
Come on. You heard him. Let's find it.
他怎麼會有解藥?
Wait. Why does Dracula have a cure?
- 我不在乎 - 我在乎
- I don't care! - I do.
他為什麼需要解藥?
Why does he need one? Why?
因為只有狼人能殺死他
Because the only thing that can kill him is a werewolf.
這就是那幅畫的意思
The painting. That's what it meant.
狼人一直都聽命于德古拉
Dracula's been using werewolves to do his bidding for centuries.
要是狼人對他反撲
Yes, but if one ever had the will to turn on him, he'd need a cure...
他就能把他變回普通人
to remove the curse and make him human before it bit him.
帶他們去…
You're going to take these two...
- 拿解藥 - 我才不去
- and lead them to the antidote. - No, I'm not.
我去  我去
Yes, I am.
午夜鐘聲一響…
Here's the plan. When the bell begins to toll midnight...
就殺死德古拉
you'll be able to kill Dracula.
我們會在同時…
We just need to find the cure...
把解藥給你
and get it into you before the final stroke.
你瘋啦? 這是什麼爛計畫?
Are you insane? What kind of plan is that?
要是你敢亂指路…
If they even suspect you of misleading them...
就斬斷他手指
clip off one of his fingers.
- 我會斬斷他別的東西 - 解藥在…
- I'll clip off something. - The tower over there...
- 高塔上 - 另一個高塔有什麼?
- that's where it is. - And what about the other tower?
- 拿來 - 那裡是…
- Give me that! - That is where...
實驗室 我不敢騙你
we reassembled the laboratory. Would I lie to you?
你想活命就不敢
Not if you wanted to live.
如果在午夜鐘響前沒拿到解藥…
Now, if I'm not cured by the twelfth stroke of midnight....
- 我下不了手 - 你一定要殺我
- I don't think I could. - You must.
來吧!
Come on.
這計畫不好
I don't like this plan.
沒辦法  小心點
We don't have a choice. Just don't get killed.
你不懂
You still don't understand.
我不怕死
It doesn't matter what happens to me.
我只想救我全家
We must save my family.
如果你遲到… 拔腿就逃
If you're late, run like hell.
別遲到
Don't be late.
去吧!快去
Now go. Go.
走開  臭東西
Get off me, you vermin from hell!
閉嘴  這是你的使命
What are you complaining about? This is why you were made!
證明人類也能創造生命
To prove that God is not the only one who can create life!
你要讓我的孩子復活
And now you must give that life to my children.
抬起來!
Up!
在那裡
There it is.
我先去
I'll go first.
卡爾!
Carl!
去死吧!
Stay as long as you like.
你想整我  我先整死你
You try to get lgor. Igor get you!
- 快去拿呀! - 你去拿
- Go ahead. Grab it. - You go ahead and grab it.
我才不要…
If there's one thing I've learned...
碰這種危險物質
it's never to be the first to stick your hand in a viscous material.
- 嚇到你們了? - 並沒有
- Did I scare you? - No.
我猜我得用點狠招
Then maybe I need to try a little harder.
我就說很危險吧!
Viscous material! What did I tell you?
快去拿
Get it!
好燙  好燙
Hot.
- 快一點! - 好
- Come on! - Yes.
快把解藥拿給范海辛 快去呀!
We've got to get the antidote to Van Helsing! Go!
你想得美
You can't go until I say you can go!
快跑呀!
Keep running, Carl!
給我過來  領死吧!
And I'll say you can go when you're dead!
天啊!
Oh, my God!
別過來  快去找解藥
What are you doing? You must find the cure!
- 我的朋友正在找 - 朋友
- My friends are doing it for me. - Friends.
對  你需要朋友嗎?
Yes. You want one?
我打不開 這會有點痛
I can't unscrew the bolts. This is gonna hurt.
我習慣了
I am accustomed to pain.
這代表你活著
It lets you know you're alive.
賜給我生命
Give me life!
再來一次我的孩子就會復活
One more bolt and my young will live.
就快好了
You're almost out, my friend!
救救我
Help me!
你應該死的
But you're supposed to die.
我想活
I want to live.
好吧!
All right!
你死了…
Be happy in the knowledge...
我會替你收屍
that I shall weep over your dead body.
撐著點
Hang on!
我來救你
I'll swing you loose!
你來晚了
You are too late, my friend.
我的孩子復活了
My children live.
那麼我只好殺了你
Then the only way to kill them is to kill you.
沒錯
Correct.
好吧!
So be it.
一
One.
不  不可能
No, this cannot be.
我們本來是同一國的
We are both part of the same grand game, Gabriel.
不必變成死對頭
But we need not find ourselves on opposite sides of the board.
快去救范海辛
Go! Go and help Van Helsing!
快點!
Now!
謝謝你
Thank you.
我的天呀! 我需要幫忙
Oh, my God! Anna, I need a little help!
快點!
Hurry!
丟過來
Throw it to me, Carl!
你跟我一樣被人利用
You are being used, Gabriel, as was l.
你也可以逃走
But I escaped. So can you.
安娜  親愛的
Anna, my love...
你的鮮血讓我青春永駐
it is your blood that shall keep me beautiful.
去死吧!
What do you think of that?
你要殺人就快下手
I think if you're going to kill someone, kill them.
廢話少說
Don't stand there talking about it.
你不懂嗎?
Don't you understand?
我們可以成為好友 好搭檔
We could be friends. Partners!
最佳戰友
Brothers-in-arms!
我當年就是被你殺死的
Did I mention that it was you who murdered me?
身為上帝的左手
It must be such a burden. Such a curse...
是多麼沉重的負擔和詛咒
to be the Left Hand of God.
我只想獲得永生
All I want is life, Gabriel.
延續我的香火
The continuation of my kind.
拿回我的戒指
And perhaps the return of my ring.
別害怕
Don't be afraid, Gabriel. Don't be afraid.
我會把你的命和記憶還給你
I shall give you back your life, your memory.
有些事忘了最好
Some things are better left forgotten.
上帝保佑
For God!
上帝原諒我
God forgive me.
她死了
She's dead.
讓她安息吧! 主啊! 願你的榮光…
"Eternal rest grant unto her, Oh, Lord, and let perpetual light...
照亮她的靈魂…
"shine upon her. On her soul and the souls of all...
"On her soul and the souls of all...
忠實信徒得到寬恕…
"the dead faithful have mercy.... "